He's eating the Detonation Clay,
which means...
(トビ)起爆粘土を自分の口で
食ってるってことは…。
I saved the best for last!
I'll kill you with this!
(デイダラ)とっておきだ。 次で殺す。
(デイダラ)トビ 逃げてろ！
Tobi, get away!
Whoa, yikes! It's the C4 Karura!
(トビ)うわぁ やべえ。 Ｃ４カルラだ。
Hurry...!
急げ～！
This was supposed to be
my trump card to kill Itachi, but...
《イタチを殺すための とっておきの
術だったんだがな うん》
《サスケ : コイツも爆弾なのか？
だとしたら でかい。
Is this a bomb too? If so...
It's huge! If this goes off...
これが爆発するとなると…》
What, you're just gonna run away?!
いきなり逃げんのかよ おい！
You really think you can escape
from my C4 Karura?!
って 逃げ切れると思ってんのか。
このＣ４カルラから。
《不発？》
It misfired...?
No... That's not it.
《いや 違う。 これは！》
What?!
I win!
オイラの勝ちだ。
Art is an explosion!
芸術は 爆発なのだ！
喝！
昇華。
Sublimate!
Damn!
クソッ。 まさか こんな…。
This can't... be happening!
sha la la some day in the future
sha la la itsuka kitto
I will for sure hold it in my hand
boku wa te ni suru nda
it will softly set ablaze
hakanaki mune ni sotto
a light in my empty heart
hikari moeteyuke
the "impulses" that makes you want to meet it
aitaku naru no shoudou
the "innocence" that makes you want to cry
nakitaku naru no junjou
they've gone into the summer fire
natsu no hi ni tobikonda
the fireflies aren't coming back
hotaru wa kaeranai
you didn't say a single word and left a kiss for me behind
anata wa nanimo iwazu kuchizuke wo nokoshite
and nodded as you still got burned
kitsuzuku mama unazuita ne
it was so sad that my life was wavering
kanashii hodo inochi yurameiteita
sha la la some day in the future
sha la la itsuka kitto
I will for sure hold it in my hand
boku wa te ni suru nda
it will softly set ablaze
hakanaki mune ni sotto
a light in my empty heart
hikari moeteyuke
sha la la my sweet lovely dear
sha la la itoshiki hito
I can also see you right now
anata mo mieteiru no
the dazzling moon will softly
mabayui tsuki ga sotto
illuminate the morning day
ashita wo terashite
and strongly and strongly shine on
tsuyoku tsuyoku kagayaite
Art
う～ん。 うん うん うん！
これぞ 最高傑作だ！
Now this is my greatest masterpiece!
よっと。
There we go!
超小型ナノサイズ爆弾Ｃ４カルラ。
The C4 Karura...
Super tiny, nano-sized explosives.
巨大デイダラを破裂させ
その爆風により➡
Using the blast created from
rupturing the giant Deidara,
explosives too small
for the human eye to see
目には見えない小型爆弾を
大気中に散布。
are dispersed into the atmosphere.
それを吸い込んだ生物は
体内のあらゆる個所に➡
Any living being that inhales them
will set off explosions internally
in all parts of the body.
爆弾をセットされる仕組み。
And these little explosions
will destroy the body
いくつもの小さな爆発は➡
細胞レベルで体内から
生物を破壊していく。
on the cellular level...
フッ 恐ろしい術だ。
A frightening jutsu...
イタチに礼を言わなきゃな。 ククッ。
I have to thank Itachi...
ククッ。 勝った！ 勝ったぞ！
オイラの芸術が！
I've won! I've won!
My art wo-!
チャクラを使い切ったようだな。
It seems you've exhausted your chakra...
動きが遅いぜ。
その目！
Your reaction was slow.
Those eyes...
目には見えぬ爆弾。
Explosives too small for
the eye to see...
だが オレの写輪眼は
チャクラを色で見分ける。
But my Sharingan can distinguish
a chakra by its color.
チャクラが練り込まれた小さな爆弾。
The mini-bombs molded with
your chakra...
オレには 煙の塊のように
はっきりと見えていたのさ。
They were as clear to me as
a cloud of smoke.
お前の滞空している場所は➡
I could also tell that you were hovering
その小型爆弾が及ばない
高さにあることもわかった。
just outside the mini-bombs'
blast range.
それに 爆弾が見えていれば
逃げるのはたやすい。
So as long as I could see the explosives,
escape was easy.
But I saw you die from my C4...
お前がＣ４で
死んだように見えたのは…。
That was my genjutsu.
オレの幻術だ。
ククッ やっぱり。
やっぱりそうだったか。
So that was it, after all...
急所は外してある。
I avoided your vital spot.
イタチの居場所を教えろ。
Now tell me where Itachi is.
フフフ… だから イタチに
礼を言わなきゃって言ったんだ。
That's why I said...
"I have to thank Itachi.".
粘土… 分身か!?
A clay... clone?!
お前の幻術は
前もって読んでたぜ！
I anticipated your genjutsu.
You're just like Itachi!
イタチと一緒だ！
二度と同じ手は食わねえぜ うん。
I never fall for the same trick twice!
《そうだ！
イタチとやった あの日から…》
Yes... Ever since
the day I fought Itachi...
((オイラを… アートを
ナメんじゃねえぞ！
Don't belittle... me... or my art!
オレの忍術は
何よりも崇高な芸術だ。 うん。
My ninjutsu is nothing
but noble, refined art!
アートを感じろ！
Feel my art!
喝！
ヘヘッ いきがってたわりには
その程度かよ！
You talked big...
but is that all you have?
終わりだ！ うん！
It's over...!
よく自分の姿を見たほうがいい。
You should take a good look
at yourself.
え？
Huh?
な… なに!?
Wh-What?!
(鬼鮫)危なかったですね。
That was close.
A little later and
you would've blown yourself up.
もう少しで
自爆するところでしたよ。
I told you he was the type to die young.
(サソリ)やっぱり
早死にするタイプだな コイツは。
幻術か… いつの間に!?
A genjutsu! When?!
(鬼鮫)初めからですよ。
From the very beginning.
From the moment you looked into
Itachi's Sharingan eye,
イタチさんの写輪眼を見たとき
すでに あなたは幻術の中。
you were under his Genjutsu.
《美しい…》
Beautiful...
《これは… 芸術だ…》
This is... art!
オイラが 他人の能力に
見入っちまうなんて…。
Damn! I became fascinated by
the abilities of another?
(あれが芸術だと？
いや認めねえ！ 認めねえぞ))
That's art? No way...
I refuse to acknowledge it!
《オレの左目は
対写輪眼用として鍛えてたのさ》
I trained my left eye to
counter the Sharingan.
幻術を解く訓練を
怠るわけねえだろ！
As if I'd neglect training
to counter genjutsu!
これで ホントの最後だ！
直接 Ｃ４をくらえ！ うん！
This time, it's over for real!
Eat my C4!
お前こそ チャクラが
足りねえようだな！
It seems you're the one lacking chakra!
You don't even have
the strength left to dodge! Huh?!
振りほどく力も
残ってねえか？ あぁ!?
やっぱりか…。
Just as I thought...
Inside are the same invisible
C4 explosives.
その中は さっきと同じ➡
目には見えねえ
Ｃ４爆弾だぜ！ うん！
Tsk! My wound hurts...
《チッ… 傷が痛え。
On top of that, I used up my chakra
with that last attack.
そのうえ 今ので
チャクラを使いきっちまったか。
What a poor piece of work...!
情けねえ駄作だぜ…》
さぁ どうする？ うん！
Now what'll you do?! Hmm?
《ありったけの雷切か》
He used what's left of
his Lightning Blade...
Your Lightning Blades won't reach me
at this distance!
この距離なら 雷切を
伸ばした攻撃も当たらねえぜ！
It's over.
終わりだ！ 喝!!
Release!
うぅ…。
勝った… オイラの勝ちだ。
I won. I'm the winner!
オイラの芸術が 勝ったぜ！
My art triumphed!
ヘヘ… ヘヘヘ… なんで!?
Why?!
うぅっ！
ど どういうことだ？
Wh-What's going on?
《これは 幻術じゃない。
This is no genjutsu...
But then...
だとしたら コイツ…
どうやって Ｃ４爆弾を…》
How... How did he disarm my C4?
お前… お前 まさか
気づいてたのか？
You...
Don't tell me you figured it out?
あぁ とっくにな。
Yeah... Quite a while back...
アンタ 写輪眼を相手にするときは➡
When facing the Sharingan,
it's basic to hide and form your seal.
印は隠して結ぶのが 基本だ。
どれだけ速かろうが
この眼で見切る。
No matter how fast you are,
these eyes will read them.
アンタの これまでの術は
全部 土遁の印だった。
Every jutsu you've used has been
with Earth Style seals.
オレの千鳥は 雷遁
そういうことだろう。
My Chidori is the Lighting Style...
Get it now?
やっぱり 気づいてやがったのか。
So you knew, after all...
じゃあ お前 さっきの雷切は
まさか…。
Then that Lightning Blade
you used was to...
土遁は 雷遁に弱い。
The Earth Style is vulnerable
to the Lightning Style.
アンタの爆弾は 雷遁を食らえば
起爆しなくなる。
Your explosives won't detonate against
my Lightning Style.
それが 弱点なんだろ？
Isn't that your weakness?
お前…。
You...!
《そうか… さっきの雷切は
自分の体に…。
I see... The Lightning Blade earlier
was to run it through yourself...
それで 体内のＣ４を
不発にしたのか》
and you de-triggered the C4
that had entered your body.
あぁ おかげで 体がボロボロだ。
Yeah... Thanks to that,
my body's in tatters.
正確には 千鳥という術だがな。
Although the correct name for
my jutsu is Chidori...
《オイラの芸術の弱点を
短時間の間に こうもハッキリと…》
He figured out the weakness of
my art in such a short time,
and so accurately...
いつ 気づいた？
When did you realize it?
地雷を食らった後だ。
After that blow from the land mine.
といっても 分析は
最初から ずっとしていた。
Although, I've been analyzing it
from the very beginning...
アンタの 初めての攻撃を
千鳥千本で射抜いた後➡
Since I countered your first attack
with Chidori Senbon.
アンタの作り出した爆弾には➡
Among the bombs you created,
some exploded and some didn't.
爆発したものと
してないものがあった。
そこで ある仮説が生まれた。
That's when I formulated a hypothesis.
仮説!?
Hypothesis...?
あのとき 爆発したのは➡
That time, the only one that exploded
was the one you threw
アンタが オレの反撃を
回避しようとして➡
新たに 投げつけた爆弾
一つだけ。
when you tried to evade my attack.
その前の オレが千鳥千本で
射抜いた爆弾は➡
All the explosives that I countered with
my Chidori Senbon didn't detonate.
すべて 起爆していなかった。
だが あれは アンタの仲間の近くにも
落ちたからな。
However, it was possible that
you purposely didn't trigger them...
わざと 起爆させなかったとも
考えられる。
because they fell close
to your comrade.
つまり 起爆しなかったのは
千鳥のおかげか➡
In other words, you weren't sure
if they didn't detonate
オレの意思か
わからなかったってことだな。
because of your Chidori or
because I didn't make them explode.
そうか… だから その二択を
地雷で確かめたのか。
I see... So that's why you tested those
two alternatives on the land mine?
そのとおりだ。
Exactly.
((Ｃ２は 地雷の足止めと
空中からの ピンポイント攻撃。
The key element of the C2
coordinated assault is
using the land mines to slow you down
この連携攻撃が ミソだ。
and finishing you off with
a pinpoint missile attack.
お前の足元には すでに
ビッシリ 地雷が敷き詰めてある。
Land mines are planted all around you!
(踏みつけただけで 自動爆破だ))
Step on one and you'll set them off!
自動爆破なら
アンタの意思とは関係ない。
If they were self-triggered,
your will was not involved.
オレの雷属性の術で➡
So I could test if my Lightning Style Jutsu
土属性の爆弾が
不発になるかどうか➡
could disarm your Earth Style bombs.
確かめることができる。
そうだ…
地面に 刀を刺したときだ。
That's right. That time I stuck my sword
into the ground...
あれは 地雷の有無を
確かめたんじゃない。
I wasn't verifying the location
of land mines.
仮説を確信に変えるために➡
I shot through them with my sword
tinged with Chidori
千鳥を帯びた刀で
地雷を射抜いたのさ。
in order to confirm my theory.
けど どうやって どうして
地雷の位置が➡
But... how?! How could you pinpoint
the position of the landmines?!
ピンポイントでわかった？
この眼は チャクラを色で見分ける…➡
This eye distinguishes chakra by its color.
そう言わなかったか？
Didn't I tell you that earlier?
地雷の位置が見えただと!?
You could see the position of
the land mines...?!
《地雷のない場所に
足場を作るために➡
He wasn't poking into the ground
to test where they were
刀を刺したわけじゃ
なかったってのか!?
and where he could step?
あれは 起爆粘土が
不発になるかどうかを➡
He was checking whether
he could disarm the Detonation Clay...
試すために…》
じゃあ もし 地雷が
不発にならずに➡
But what would you have done
if the land mines exploded?!
爆発したら
どうするつもりだった？
ただの二択だ。
It was one or the other.
But I had another back-up plan.
そうなれば オレには
もう一つ手があった。
披露する機会は なかったがな。
Although I didn't have a chance
to demonstrate it...
《コイツ… まだ他に 何か術を》
This guy...
He even had another jutsu...
あっ！
チッ…。
イタチは どこにいる？
Where is Itachi?
クッ…。
ヘッ… いきがっても
もうギリギリじゃねえかよ。
You may try to look good,
but you're barely managing too.
急激に
チャクラがなくなったようだな。
It seems your chakra got drastically low.
ヘヘッ 勝ちだぜ。
I win. I still have
Detonation Clay to... Huh?!
オイラには起爆粘土が… ん!?
この状況… 少しは動揺してみろよ
テメエは！ うん？
Under these conditions,
shouldn't you be panicking a little?
今度こそ
オイラの芸術で殺されんだぜ。
This time, my art will kill you for sure!
ヘッ… ヘヘッ…。
ハッハッハッハッ！
そういうとこが ムカつくんだよ！
テメエら兄弟の そういうとこが!!
That's what pisses me off about you!
Both of you brothers!
クール 装ってんじゃねえぞ！
Don't pretend to be so cool!
その目だ。
その余裕こいた目が目障りなんだ。
Those eyes!
That overconfident eye irritates me!
オイラの芸術を否定するかのような
その目が許せねえ！
As if it denies my art! It's unforgivable!
オイラの芸術を見て
少しの驚嘆も表さない その目が。
Those eyes which show absolutely
no respect for my art...
オイラの芸術をムシする その目が
許せねえんだよ!!
Those eyes that ignore my art...
are unforgivable!
ハァ ハァ ハァ…。
そんなものは眼中にない。
I couldn't care less about such a thing.
それより イタチの居場所を教えろ。
Never mind that. Tell me where Itachi is.
写輪眼まで引っ込めたか。
どこまでも ナメやがって！
So you've drawn back your Sharingan...
You really take me lightly!
ヘヘヘ…。
オイラの究極芸術だ。
This is my ultimate art...!
これから オイラは自爆する。
Now I will detonate myself.
《コイツ…》
He's...!
死んで オイラは芸術になる。
With death, I will become art.
This never-before-seen explosion
will leave
今までにない爆発は この地に
今までにない傷跡を残し➡
a never-before-seen scar on this land.
そして オイラの芸術は
今までにない称賛を受けるだろう。
And...! My art will win
never-before-seen admiration!
《トビ… 悪いな》
Sorry, Tobi...
オイラの称賛のなか
テメエは確実に死ぬ！
In the midst of my admiration,
you will definitely die!
半径10キロが爆発範囲だ。
An explosion that will cover
a ten-kilometer radius...
逃げきれやしねえぜ うん！
You won't be able to get away!
さぁ 怯えろ…
驚嘆しろ！ 絶望しろ!!
Now, tremble with fear!
Be in awe! Despair!
泣きわめけ！ オイラの芸術は…。
Scream!
My art is...
(デイダラ)喝!!
Release!
(デイダラ)爆発だ!!
An explosion!
keep your pants and shirt on even if you're unable to do it right now
ima dekinakute mo aseranaide awatenaide
you should believe in yourself and take it at your own pace
kimi no mai peesu de jibun shinjite yukkuri ikeba ii
life always throws you curveballs and the reason of that is
yo kono yo wa hitosujinawa de ikanai sore wa naze nara
it's a test made by God so that's why it's quite hard
kamisama ga tsukutta tesuto dakara muzukashii nda
arts? science? or rather how about ethics?
bunkei rikei mushiro doutoku kimi nara kore wo dou toku
this is just like life so put your heart and soul into seriousness
kore wa maru de jinsei dakara uchikomu shinken ni
we worry ourselves lose ourselves and we keep asking ourselves questions
bokura wa nayamu mayou nandomo jibun ni toikakeru
we aren't one and relentesly persue our search for answers
hitotsu ja nai kotae sagashi gamushara ni oikakeru
keep your pants and shirt on even if you're unable to do it right now
ima dekinakute mo aseranaide awatenaide
you should believe in yourself and take it at your own pace
kimi no mai peesu de jibun shinjite yukkuri ikeba ii
the current me would tell me that if I was from the future
mirai no bokura nara ima no boku ni oshiete agerareru
you should keep pursuing it until your efforts change yourself
kimi no doryoku ga jishin ni kawaru toki made oitsuzukereba ii
Next Episode
Naruto, there are signs that
Sasuke-kun was just here.
- What?!
- It's very vague, but his scent still lingers.
(ウルティア)ゼレフ…。
I'd say there was a battle here.
Then let's go after Sasuke immediately!
あなたは 私のもの。
We can't.
誰にも… 誰にも渡さない。
Why not?
The scent stops here.
In a case like this,
either Sasuke was erased without
a trace in the explosion, or...
私は あなたを世界の王にする。
Next time: "Disappearance"
Disappearance
大魔法世界のために…。